A Guide to the Alfred E. Cohn papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA802 FA802
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Alfred E. Cohn papers, Rockefeller University Faculty, 45 record storage cartons, 1 oversize box.
  - Sydenham Hospital/Institution Pamphlet, fund-raising, correspondence S-W, constitution and by-laws, circa 1947-1948
    - [Pamphlet and memo. Multiple copies of memo discarded by archivist], 1947 March 20 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Memo [Multiple copies discarded], 1947 February 17 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - [Miscellaneous papers re SI pamphlet, including Cohn drafts] (Box 12, Folder 8-11)
    - Sydenham Hospital. Statement to public [dated "Lincoln's Birthday, 1947"] (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - [Printed materials, including "A Step That May Well be Epochal" booklet, and statement on first year of operation of SH] (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - [Letters re SI pamphlet]
      - Bayne-Jones, S. (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Beard, Charles (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Cane, Melville (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Duggan, Stephen (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Farrell, Mrs. W. Elliston (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Fishbein, Morris (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Hyam, Margot (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Isaacs, Stanley M. (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Levey, Stanley (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Lerner, Max (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Proskauer, Richard (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Richards, Augustus L. (Box 12, Folder 14)
        [Note from Felix Frankfurter].
      - Ryle, John A. (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Shryock, Richard H. (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Steele, Katherine (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Taschman, Max (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Taylor, Harold (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Waddell, Catherine Hughes------------- (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Visiting Chiefs of Service (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - [Cohn ms. drafts and notes] (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - T (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Thorndike, Dr. W.T.S. (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Tate, Lillie B. (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Thompson, Edward I. (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Tobias, Channing H. (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - United Hospital Fund (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Urban League (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Various pamphlets (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - S (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Schaefer, J.F. (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Saltonstall, John L. Jr. (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Seegal, David (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Silvera, John D. (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Shaw, G. Howland (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Sheehan, Donal (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Silve, Dave (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Skouras, Spyros (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Smith, Cornelius M. (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Smith, Ferdinand (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Spellman, Cardinal Francis (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Sonnenberg, Benjamin (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Spingarn, Arthur B. (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Spellman, F. Cardinal (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Stiefel, Babette M. (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Steichen, Kate Robinson (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Stephens, Roderick (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Stewart, Charles I. (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Stone, Abraham (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Sulzberger, Marion B. (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Switzer, Mary E.] (Box 12, Folder 22)
      [includes note from E.R. Murrow/AEC 1 July 1947].
    - Swope, Herbert Bayard (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Sydoscope [employee newsletter], 1947 November (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - New York hospitals statistics (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Watson, Mr. (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Waddell, Mrs. Chauncey L. (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - (Catherine Hughes) (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Wilson, Charles (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - White, Walter (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Weissman, I. Oscar (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - [Assorted printed and duplicated materials] (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - [Papers from 3-ring binder] (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Constitution and by-laws
      - General (Box 12, Folder 27-30)
      - Article VI. Irving Parker, 1947 July 31 (Box 12, Folder 31)
      - By-laws, Irving Parker, 1948 May 27 (Box 12, Folder 32)
      - By-laws, Irving Parker, 1947 November 3 (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - [Cohn handwritten drafts] (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Committees. NY State Against Discrimination. President's Committee Civil Liberties. Mayor's Committee on Unity (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Refugee materials D-N, circa 1933-1945
    - D
      - Duggan, Stephen (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Drury, Betty (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - de Körösy, Francis (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - de Madariaga (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Doskow, Ambrose (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Dublin, L.I. (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Duke, Ruth E. (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Dunn, L.C. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Demuth, F.
      - [General] (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - Academies. Soc. Protection Sci. and Learning (Adams). Demuth. Madariaga Loewenstein (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Treviranus. Dr. G.R. re Dr. F. Demuth (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - E (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - Elwood, Everett S. (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - Emmanuel, Miss (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - Erdmann, William (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - Ettinghausen, Richard E. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Experts Committee (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Farrand, Livingston Fine, Jacob (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Fishbein, Morris (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Fryda, Prof. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Fuerst, W.F. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Furcht, Louis (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Flexner, Bernard (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Financial statements (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Farmer, Laurence (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Frankfurter, Felix (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - G
      - Ginsberg, Marie (Box 13, Folder 12)
      - Goldman, Hetty (Box 13, Folder 12)
      - Goldman, Henry (Box 13, Folder 12)
      - Goldforb, A.J. (Box 13, Folder 12)
      - Gregg, Alan (Box 13, Folder 12)
      - Gross, Leo (Ludwik) (Box 13, Folder 12)
      - Graef, Irving re students (Box 13, Folder 13)
      - German-Jewish Emigration Council (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Hecht, Selig (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - H (Box 13, Folder 16)
      - Hamilton, Alice
      - Harkness, Edward S.
      - Henson, Francis A.
      - Hess, Sara (Mrs. Alfred F.)
      - Heyman, David M.
      - Hirst, Albert
      - Horkheimer, Max
      - Hirschmann, I.A.
      - Hofheimer Foundation
      - Hyam, Mrs. Katherine E.
    - I (Box 13, Folder 17)
      - [Ivins, William] "Billee" International News Service (Box 13, Folder 17)
      - Internships and residences (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Joint Distribution Committee [American Jewish] Hyman, J.C. Leavitt, M.A. (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - J (Box 13, Folder 19)
      - Jackh, E. (Box 13, Folder 19)
      - Jordan, H.P. (Box 13, Folder 19)
      - JSSA (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Johnson, Alvin University in Exile Grad faculty (Box 13)
      - Emerg. Committee. Scholars (Box 13, Folder 20)
      - General correspondence (Box 13, Folder 21)
      - Emergency Committee - Physicians (Box 13, Folder 22)
      - [Correspondence, documents re University in Exile] (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - K (Box 13, Folder 24)
      - Kotschnig, W. (Box 13, Folder 24)
      - Kahn, Bernhard (Box 13, Folder 24)
      - Kandel, I.L. (Box 13, Folder 24)
      - Keppel, F.P. (Box 13, Folder 24)
      - Klemperer, Paul (Box 13, Folder 24)
      - Kligler, I.J. (Box 13, Folder 24)
      - Knauth, Felix [includes reports on visits to colleges and universities], 1939 October-1940 January (Box 13, Folder 24)
      - Kubie, Lawrence S. (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Krueger, Joseph [includes report, "A program of aid for German Jewish refugee students by the Phi Sigma Delta fraternity,"], 1936 March 25 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - L (Box 13, Folder 26)
      - League of Nations Union (Box 13, Folder 26)
      - Lederer, Emil (Box 13, Folder 26)
      - Levy, Mrs. David M. (Adele) (Box 13, Folder 26)
      - Levy, Sylvain (Box 13, Folder 26)
      - Lewisohn, Richard (Box 13, Folder 26)
      - Libman, Emanuel (Box 13, Folder 26)
      - Licktenstein, L. (Box 13, Folder 26)
      - Levene, P.A. (Box 13, Folder 26)
      - Liebman, Charles J. (Box 13, Folder 26)
      - Lisowski, Eunice (Box 13, Folder 26)
      - Littauer, Rudolf (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Luxembourg stamp issue (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - M (Box 13, Folder 28)
      - Murrow, E.R. (Box 13, Folder 28)
      - Mack, Judge Julian (Box 13, Folder 28)
      - May, Sigmund H. (Box 13, Folder 28)
      - Magnes, Judah L. (Box 13, Folder 28)
      - May, Herbert L. (Box 13, Folder 28)
      - Mead, Nelson P. (Box 13, Folder 28)
      - Michaelis, Dr. (Box 13, Folder 28)
      - Michaelis, Ilse (Box 13, Folder 28)
      - Miller, Edgar G. Jr. (Box 13, Folder 28)
      - Miller, Valentin (Box 13, Folder 28)
      - Moore, Norman S. (Box 13, Folder 28)
      - Modern Medicine (Box 13, Folder 28)
      - Mulhern, Donald (Box 13, Folder 28)
      - Murray, H.A. (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - McDonald, James G. (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - McLean, Franklin C. (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Minutes of the Emergency Committee in Aid of Displaced Foreign Physicians (Medical Scientists) (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Minutes of the Subcommittee on Placements. Displaced Foreign [Medical] Scientists (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - N (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - National Coordinating Committee Fund, Inc. (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - Neblett, Thomas (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - Notgemeinschaft deutscher Wissenschaftler im Ausland (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - Reports, Natl. Comm. Resettlement of For. Phys. (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - National Coordinating Committee for aid to refugees and emigrants coming from Germany. C. Razovsky Sec'y (Box 13, Folder 35-36)
    - National Refugee Service (Box 13)
      - Prof. Joseph Chamberlain (Box 13, Folder 37)
      - Miss Betty Drury (beginning Dec 44) (Box 13, Folder 37)
      - William Haber (Box 13, Folder 38)
      - Charles H. Jordan (Box 13, Folder 39)
      - Nicholas Michelson (Box 13, Folder 39)
      - Cecilia Razovsky (Box 13, Folder 39)
      - [Miscellaneous reports and papers] (Box 13, Folder 40-41)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - Veterans Administration, circa 1924-1947 (Box 14)
    - Medical Council Papers, circa 1924-1939 (Box 14)
      [removed from "Acco" binders; titles are from labels on binder covers].
      - Dr. Alfred E. Cohn, Counselor. Medical Council - Veterans Administration [re 13th conference], 1939 October (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - [Documents re Medical Council], circa 1924-1925 (Box 14, Folder 2-3)
      - Seventh Conference..., 1927 May (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - Ninth Conference..., 1928 November (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - Eleventh Conference..., 1930 March (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - [Program of 12th conference; rep. of 11th conference] (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Bolte, [Charles G.], circa 1946-1947 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Bradley [Omar] - Hawley [Paul R.], circa 1946 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - [Miscellaneous] (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Monthly reports on the U.S. Veterans Bureau, 1924 November-1925 February (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - F.E.A. [Foreign Economic Administration] Organization, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - U.N.R.R.A. [United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration. Memos], circa 1943 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - United States Naval Reserve (Box 14, Folder 14)
      - [correspondence re possible physiological/psychological studies of aviators], 1940
    - National Resources Planning Board. James C. O'Brien. National Roster of Scientific and Specialized Personnel, circa 1941-1944 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Office of Foreign Relief, etc. (Box 14)
      - Boudreau, Frank G. Miscellaneous (Box 14, Folder 16)
      - Gunn, Selskar M., 1943 (Box 14, Folder 17)
        [includes AEC memo draft and typescript, "Memorandum on the Current Needs of China (Abstract)", 5 pp. encls. AEC/Gunn 31 Mar 43].
      - Lehmann, Governor, circa 1942-1944 (Box 14, Folder 18)
      - Health Committee Minutes, circa 1943 (Box 14, Folder 19)
      - Maternity Care and Child Health [Subcomm.] (Box 14, Folder 20)
      - Nutrition [Subcomm.] (Box 14, Folder 20)
      - Sanitation [Subcomm.] (Box 14, Folder 20)
      - Tropical Diseases [Subcomm.] (Box 14, Folder 20)
      - Tuberculosis [Subcomm.] (Box 14, Folder 20)
      - Memos [filed with legal size] (Box 14, Folder 21)
      - Newspaper clippings O.F.R.R.O., O.F.E.C., F.E.A., U.N.R.R.A. (Box 14, Folder 22)
      - O.F.E.C. [Office of Foreign Economic Coordination], circa 1943 (Box 14, Folder 23)
      - O.F.E.C. (Box 14, Folder 24)
      - Area Committee for Central Europe (Box 14, Folder 24)
      - Area Committee - East Indies (Box 14, Folder 24)
      - French Area Committee (Box 14, Folder 24)
      - Area Committees (Box 14, Folder 25)
      - Greece and Balkans (Box 14, Folder 25)
      - Italy (Box 14, Folder 25)
      - Low. Countries [Filed with legal size] (Box 14, Folder 25)
      - O.F.E.C. Coordinating Committee and Supply Subcomm. [filed with legal size] (Box 14, Folder 26)
      - Coordinating Comm. Policy -Notes (Box 14, Folder 27)
      - O.F.E.C. Policy Comm. [filed with legal size] (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - The Burden of Diseases (Box 14)
      - Discarded sheets, [various typescript pages] (Box 14, Folder 29)
      - New York Heart Campaign -Miss Lingg [Newspaper clippings], circa 1947-1948 (Box 14, Folder 30)
      - [Loose papers: mss, notes, graphs, correspondence], circa 1946-1949 (Box 14, Folder 31)
      - [Miscellaneous newspaper clippings] (Box 14, Folder 32)
      - Burden of Diseases — tables (Box 14, Folder 33)
      - [Assorted reprints and booklets on cancer, heart disease, syphilis, TB, diabetes, typhus, pneumonia, longevity, marriage] (Box 14, Folder 34)
      - [Third revision of Burden of Diseases], 1948 January (Box 14, Folder 35-36)
      - [Correspondence], 1949 July-September (Box 14, Folder 37)
      - [Second revision], 1947 January (Box 14, Folder 38-39)
  - Student organizations: International Student Service, Student Service of America; World Student Service Fund, circa 1945-1947 (Box 15)
    See also folder 9.
    - Rowland, Wilmina Ruml, Bearsley (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Shuster, George N. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Sharp, Bertram L. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Tax exemption (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Taylor, Harold [re bacteriology text by Madeleine Grant] (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Tremper, Janis (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - "Université 46" subscriptions (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Whitecotton, Alice T. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Wieting, C. Maurice (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Wolfers, Arnold (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - [Sheets from unlabeled Cohn address book; completed cards for ISS contributions] (Box 15, Folder 1a)
    - World Student Service Fund (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - Dupre, J. Huntley
      - Fisher, Edgar J.
      - Kitchen, W.J.
      - Shapiro, Clara
      - Minutes, Gen. Comm.
      - Minutes, Exec. Comm.
      - Contributions
      - Newsletter, reports, etc.
    - [Loose papers: assorted printed and duplicated materials re I.S.S.] (Box 15, Folder 3-4)
    - [From binder: "Plan for a National Morale Service...", Committee for National Morale], 1941 February (Box 15, Folder 5-7)
    - [From binder: "A Department of Documentation and Bibliography and bibliographical material in support of the memoranda, " Comm. Natl. Morale], 1941 February 17 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - [Assorted booklets and publications from student organizations] (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - World's Fair [New York City], 1939 (Box 15)
      - Calver, Homer N. (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - Ciba Company, Mr. Brewer (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - Dr. [Louis I.] Dublin (Box 15, Folder 12)
      - Dr. [Bruno] Gerhard (Box 15, Folder 13)
      - Miscellaneous. Dr. Hart - Dr. Roesler, etc. (Box 15, Folder 14)
      - Dr. [George] Levene (Box 15, Folder 15)
      - Dr. Gerald Wendt (Box 15)
      - Minutes (Box 15, Folder 16)
      - [Miscellaneous notes and papers] [New York World's Fair World Vol. 1 Nos. 1 and 3; filed with flat oversize box] (Box 15, Folder 16)
      - [Building plans, medical and public health; filed in map case] (Box 15, Folder 16)
      - Miscellaneous. Luncheon -Agenda, etc. (Box 15, Folder 17)
      - [Loose papers: notes and typescripts, possibly for exhibit captions] (Box 15, Folder 18)
      - World's Fair pamphlet (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Veterans Administration (Box 15)
      - [Printed reports] (Box 15, Folder 20)
      - [Conference material, Medical Council of the United States Veterans' Bureau, with handwritten list of conference dates and numbers] (Box 15, Folder 21-23)
      - [From binder: "General orders, regulations..". Medical Council. Photostats of two organizational charts, filed in map case], circa 1924 (Box 15, Folder 24-27)
      - Monthly reports of Veterans' Bureau, circa 1924 (Box 15, Folder 28)
      - [From binder: "Data for Second Conference..." ], 1924 November (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Personal correspondence
    - "Investigations and other publications by the Members of the Staff of the Hospital of The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research", 1920-1930 1930-1937 (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
      [Includes notes for revisions, newspaper clippings on RIMR staff for biographies. Cf. Hospital Studies, Records and indexes].
    - Cole, Rufus D. (Box 16)
      - circa 1911-1921 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - circa 1922-1928 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - circa 1929-1937 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - circa 1938-1943 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - circa 1944-1952, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Flexner, Abraham (Box 16)
      - 1921-1924 (Box 16, Folder 8)
      - 1925-1927 1943 1950-1952 1956 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Flexner, Bernard (Box 16)
      - 1923-1927 (Box 16, Folder 10)
      - 1928-1939 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Flexner, Simon (Box 16)
      - 1914-1920 (Box 16, Folder 12)
      - 1921 January-May (Box 16, Folder 13)
      - 1921 September-1922 December (Box 16, Folder 14)
      - 1923 (Box 16, Folder 15)
      - 1924 (Box 16, Folder 16)
      - 1925 (Box 16, Folder 17)
      - 1926 (Box 16, Folder 18)
      - 1927 (Box 16, Folder 19)
      - 1928 (Box 16, Folder 20)
      - 1929-1930 (Box 16, Folder 21)
      - 1931-1933 (Box 16, Folder 22)
      - 1934-1935 (Box 16, Folder 23)
      - 1936-1939 (Box 16, Folder 24)
      - 1940-1945 (Box 16, Folder 25)
      - 80th birthday, 1943 March 25 (Box 16, Folder 26)
      - Medical history (Box 16, Folder 27)
        [Closed except by special permission. Filed with A.E. Cohn Closed material].
    - Flexner, Mrs. Simon, 1933 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - [Frankfurter, Felix Original note redisposition of file: "Complete file of correspondence 1920 to date sent to Supreme Court of the U.S. Washington 25 D.C. November 30, 1960."] (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Kessel, Leo and Evelyn P., 1923-1935 (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - Laski, Harold J. (Box 16)
      - "What do we mean by victory?", circa 1942 (Box 16, Folder 31)
        [Ms. and typescript ca 1942].
      - 1933-1940 (Box 16, Folder 32)
      - 1941-1945 (Box 16, Folder 33)
      - 1946-1949 (Box 16, Folder 34)
      - 1950 (Box 16, Folder 35)
    - Lewis, H.K. and Co. Ltd. (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - Lewis, W.H. Confidential (sic), 1936-1940 (Box 16, Folder 37)
    - Lim, Prof. Robert K.S., 1925-1927 (Box 16, Folder 38)
    - Longcope, Warfield T. (Box 16)
      - 1923-1931 (Box 16, Folder 39)
      - 1932-1943 (Box 16, Folder 40)
      - Janet Longcope, 1948-1952 (Box 16, Folder 41)
    - Mackenzie, Sir James] (Box 16)
      - [Photos refiled in A.E. Cohn biographical box], 1909-1910 (Box 16, Folder 42)
      - 1911-1915 (Box 16, Folder 43)
      - 1918-1925 (Box 16, Folder 44)
      - Envelopes (Box 16, Folder 45)
      - Posthumous correspondence and papers, 1926-1954 (Box 16, Folder 46)
    - Magnes, J., 1923 1927 (Box 16, Folder 47)
    - Mansfeld, Gottold, 1923 (Box 16, Folder 48)
    - May, Herbert L., 1927 (Box 16, Folder 49)
    - Rockefeller, John D. Sr. [re medical care of], circa 1927-1937 (Box 16)
      Closed except by special permission. Filed with A.E. Cohn Closed material.
    - Sabin, Florence R. (Box 16)
      - 1930 1934-1938 undated (Box 16, Folder 51)
      - 1940-1941 (Box 16, Folder 52)
      - 1942-1953 (Box 16, Folder 53)
    - Welch, William H., 1925-1930 (Box 16, Folder 54)
  - Background material on public health, circa 1940s (Box 17)
  - Committee on Research in Medical Economics, circa 1936-1939 (Box 17)
  - Oxford University Press/The University of Chicago Press, ca 1942-53, primarily re publication of The Burden of Diseases by Cohn and Lingg (Box 17)
  - New York Heart Association, 1948 Park, Edwards A. / Pediatric Clinic 1927-1932 (Box 17)
  - Physicians in Industry, 1928-1930 Psychiatry, Group for the Advancement of 1948-1949 (Box 17)
  - Physiological Congress, International, circa 1929-1934 (Box 17)
  - New York Academy of Medicine, circa 1929-1935 (Box 17)
  - Material on public health, circa 1940 (Box 17)
    - [cohn 2-page holograph], 1946 August 12 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - [Reprints] (Box 17, Folder 2-3)
    - [Newspaper clippings], circa 1947 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - [Magazine articles], circa 1947 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - [Booklets, reports, memoranda, data on public health] (Box 17, Folder 6-7)
    - "On the State of the Public Health during Six Years of War. Report of the Chief Medical Officer of the Ministry of Health 1939-45. London: His Majesty's Stationery Office, 1946" (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Sir John Orr, Fighting for What? (London: Macmillan and Co. Ltd.), 1942 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Committee on Research in Medical Economics, Dr. Michael Davis, Chairman, Mr. P. Kellogg, Sec., circa 1936-1939 (Box 17)
    - 1936 December-1937 December (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - 1938 January-June (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - 1938 July-December (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - 1939 January-November (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - [Articles, memoranda, reports] (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Oxford University Press, primarily re publication of The Burden of Diseases, circa 1942-1952 (Box 17)
    - Cushman, John, 1951-1953 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Nicholson, Margaret, 1950-1951 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Lingg, Miss, 1948-1952 (Box 17, Folder 15)
      - [Outline, nd, and drafts of preface], 1949
    - Begg, John A., 1950-1953 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Gregory, Miss, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Cane, Melville H. re contract [copy of contract filed with Cohn legal size] (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - [Miscellaneous correspondence with O.U.P. ca 1946-47, not Burden of Diseases], circa 1946-1947 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Blumgart, Herrmann L., 1946 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Garton, Russell I., 1946-1950 (Box 17, Folder 19)
      [Correspondence re Cohn suggestions for books, includes exchange with A. Szent-Györgyi Jan-Feb 1949].
    - Sales Department (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Wilson, Frank N., 1946 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Walck, Henry Z. (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - [Miscellaneous correspondence], circa 1942-1945 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Vaudrin, Philip, 1950 (Box 17, Folder 21)
      [Includes drafts of Cohn "Memorandum on a Proposed Book on The Scientific Life of James Mackenzie."].
    - Gregg, Alan, 1948 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Howe, John, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Palmer, Andrew E., 1950-1951 (Box 17, Folder 23)
      [Includes drafts by Cohn for Burden of Diseases circular].
    - Vaudrin, Philip [re publication of The Burden of Diseases, includes copy of letter, F. Frankfurter/ Cohn, 9 Jan 1951], circa 1948-1951 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Publicity, circa 1949-1951 (Box 17, Folder 25)
      [Includes synopsis of Burden, and 1950 Cohn biographical sketch].
  - University of Chicago Press (Box 17)
    - Correspondence re publication of Cohn-Lingg book, originally entitled Public Health in the United States Registration Area, 1945 April-1947 May (Box 17, Folder 26)
      Includes correspondence with C. Philip Miller and Franklin C. McLean.
    - Correspondence re publication of Cohn-Lingg book, originally entitled Public Health in the United States Registration Area, 1947 June-1948 June (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - [Extra copies of Cohn-Lingg book correspondence] (Box 17, Folder 28)